Okay we are over here at tub number 2 where we are going to install a PVC pipe drainage system and this pipe doesn't have any holes in it.
You can buy a pipe that is perforated cause this is a thin wall sewer type pipe.
But the problem is with a thin wall sewer pipe that you will buy, it is going to have holes on exactly sides of each other and we are not going to drill like that.
We are going to drill our holes so that the water holes are on the bottom of the pipe but not 180 degrees to each other.
We are going to drill them so that they are just kind of around the corner from each other.
Then we will give an improved way of getting the water out while impeding the infiltration of dirt and many things that will get into there to choke up our little system.
These holes are about a half inch diameter.
This is a speed borer.
It is kind of a generic name that is used for the drill bit or flat spade bit that some people call them.
That does a real nice job of drilling but you can see how we drill primarily on one side of the pipe and there is a reason for that.
Now we are going to plug the ends of this pipe so that we don't have dirt coming in to the pipes.
On the ends, we are just going to use a can to put in the end and we are going to hold it in place with a little piece of stick.
We are going to do that on both ends of the pipe to provide a barrier for the infiltration of dirt that will choke up our drainage system, like that.